<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
            <page> page 1 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<front> THE HIGH COURT OF DELHI AT NEW DELHI <lb/>% Judgment Reserved on: 20.01.2011 <lb/>Judgment Pronounced on: 31.01.2011 <lb/>+ CS(OS) No. 496/2009 <lb/>MS. DIVYA SOOD <lb/>PROPRIETOR M/S. THE BODY CARE ..…Plaintiff <lb/>- versus - <lb/>MS. RENU BAJAJ <lb/>PROPRIETOR M/S. PERFECT BODY CARE .....Defendant <lb/>Advocates who appeared in this case: <lb/>For the Plaintiff: Mr. M.K. Miglani and Mr. Kapil Kumar <lb/>For the Defendant: None. <lb/>CORAM:- <lb/>HON’BLE MR JUSTICE V.K. JAIN <lb/></front>
      
            <body> 1. Whether Reporters of local papers may <lb/>be allowed to see the judgment? <lb/>Yes <lb/>2. To be referred to the Reporter or not? <lb/>Yes <lb/>3. Whether the judgment should be reported <lb/>Yes <lb/>in Digest? <lb/>V.K. JAIN, J <lb/>1. <lb/>This is a suit for permanent injunction, rendition <lb/>of accounts and damages. The plaintiff Ms. Divya Sood, <lb/>who is carrying business under the name and style M/s <lb/>THE BODY CARE in engaged in providing beauty and health <lb/>care services through slimming centres, beauty clinics, <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 2 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>spas, etc. The case of the plaintiff is that she began her <lb/>operation in the year 1997 and is now recognized as the <lb/>leader in providing beauty and health services, through a <lb/>team of dedicated and trained professionals, who are <lb/>acknowledged to be the best trained in the industry. She <lb/>also claims to be well known for setting up professional and <lb/>ethical standards and claims reputation as a world-class <lb/>beauty and health care specialists. She is operating 23 <lb/>beauty body and health care clinics all over the country <lb/>with branches in all major Indian cities. <lb/>2. <lb/>The case of the plaintiff is that the mark THE <lb/>BODY CARE was coined and adopted by her in the year <lb/>2000 and since then she has been continuously, <lb/>uninterruptedly and extensively using the aforesaid mark. <lb/>She has also applied for the registration of the mark THE <lb/>BODY CARE and her application was advertised in <lb/>Trademark Journal on 18 th November 2003. The plaintiff <lb/>also claims a unique and distinctive reputation of the <lb/>trademark/label of THE BODY CARE and claims it to be an <lb/>original artistic work, within the meaning of Section 2(d) of <lb/>the Copyright Act, 1957. The plaintiff has been granted <lb/>copyright registration in respect of the said artistic work <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 3 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>vide registration No. A-71352/2005. <lb/>The plaintiff has <lb/>claimed revenue of Rs.19,10,38,917/-in the year 2005-06, <lb/>Rs.18,34,73,107/-<lb/>in <lb/>the <lb/>year <lb/>2006-07 <lb/>and <lb/>Rs.13,42,06,684/-between April to December 2007. She <lb/>also claimed to have incurred advertisement expenditure of <lb/>Rs.2,27,39,315/-, Rs.2,08,15,930/-and Rs.1,68,99,309/-<lb/>respectively during these periods. This is also the case of the <lb/>plaintiff that on account of the long, continuance and <lb/>extensive use, coupled with extensive sales promotion <lb/>activities, the trademark/label THE BODY CARE has <lb/>acquired enviable goodwill and impeccable trade reputation <lb/>and has come to be associated solely and exclusively with <lb/>the plaintiff and, therefore, the use of an identical and/or <lb/>deceptively similar trademark by another person for <lb/>same/similar goods/services is bound to be considered by <lb/>the public as user by the plaintiff in one manner or the <lb/>other. <lb/>3. <lb/>Defendant Renu Bajaj is carrying business under <lb/>the name and style of M/s. Perfect Body Care. It is alleged <lb/>that the trademark/label PERFECT BODY CARE being used <lb/>by the defendant is identical and/or deceptively similar to <lb/>the trademark/label of the plaintiff in writing style, get-up <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 4 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>and colour combination and the defendant has deliberately <lb/>copied the writing style, get-up and distinctive pink and <lb/>white colour combination of the plaintiff&apos;s trademark/label <lb/>with a view to trade upon the benefit earned by the plaintiff. <lb/>It has also been stated that the defendant is carrying <lb/>business at B-291, Saraswati Vihar,1 st Floor, Outer Ring <lb/>Road, Pitam Pura, New Delhi where business was earlier <lb/>being carried by the plaintiff from January 1998 to October <lb/>2001. It is also alleged that the persons who avail services <lb/>of the plaintiff come from all walks of life, including illiterate <lb/>and unwary customers, who demand and recognize services <lb/>of <lb/>the plaintiff <lb/>by the unique and distinctive <lb/>trademark/label adopted and being used by her. <lb/>The <lb/>plaintiff has, therefore, claimed an injunction restraining <lb/>the defendant from providing, marketing, selling and <lb/>offering or advertising health and beauty care services <lb/>under the trademark/label PERFECT BODY CARE or any <lb/>other trademark/label which would infringe the registered <lb/>copyright of the plaintiff in label THE BODY CARE. She has <lb/>also sought injunction restraining the defendant from <lb/>passing off her services as those of the plaintiff. She has <lb/>also claimed rendition of accounts and damages amounting <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 5 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>to Rs.20 Lacs from the defendant. <lb/>4. <lb/>The defendant was proceeded ex parte vide order <lb/>dated May 21, 2010. Earlier the defendant failed to appear <lb/>before Delhi High Court Mediation and Conciliation Centre, <lb/>to which the matter was referred for making efforts for an <lb/>amicable resolution of the disputes between the parties. <lb/>5. <lb/>The plaintiff has filed the affidavit of one Mr. B.P. <lb/>Sood by way of ex parte evidence. In his affidavit Mr. Sood <lb/>has supported on Oath, the case setup in the plaint and has <lb/>stated that the plaintiff began her operations in the year <lb/>1997 at a small beauty clinic in Patel Nagar and her <lb/>business has since grown in leaps and bounds and she has <lb/>become one of the premier beauty and health care service <lb/>provider in the Country. He has further stated that the <lb/>plaintiffs is widely recognized as the leader in providing <lb/>beauty and health care services and she offers <lb/>comprehensive beauty and health care packages through a <lb/>team of dedicated and trained professionals. He has also <lb/>claimed that plaintiff is known for setting up professional <lb/>and ethical standards in the industry and has established <lb/>reputation as a world class beauty and health care <lb/>specialist. He has also stated that the trademark/label THE <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 6 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>BODY CARE is being used by the plaintiff openly, <lb/>continuously and extensively since the year 2000 and it has <lb/>acquired a secondary meaning connoting and denoting to <lb/>the members of trade and customers at large as the <lb/>trademark exclusively of the plaintiff. He has also stated <lb/>that the defendant was offering services from premises <lb/>No.B-291, Saraswati Vihar, 1 st Floor, Outer Ring Road, <lb/>Pitam Pura, New Delhi from where the plaintiff was earlier <lb/>carrying business between January 1998 to October 2001 <lb/>using the trademark/label THE BODY CARE. <lb/>6. <lb/>Ex.PW1/3 are the list of 54 beauty and health care <lb/>clinics, which the plaintiff has established in various States. <lb/>Ex.PW1/44 and Ex.PW1/45 are the certificates issued by <lb/>the Chartered Accountant of the plaintiff, which show that <lb/>the turnover of the plaintiff was Rs. 19,10,38,917/-in the <lb/>year 2005-06, Rs.18,34,73,107/-and Rs.13,42,06,684/-<lb/>between April to December 2007 and that she incurred <lb/>advertisement <lb/>expenditure <lb/>of <lb/>Rs.2,27,39,315/-, <lb/>Rs.2,08,15,930/-and Rs.1,68,99,309/-respectively during <lb/>these periods. <lb/>7. <lb/>The deposition of PW-1 Shri B.P. Sood, coupled <lb/>with the list Ex. PW-1/3 shows that the plaintiff has <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 7 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>established as many as 54 Beauty and Health Care clinics <lb/>since the time she adopted the trademark THE BODY <lb/>CARE. The certificates Ex.PW-1/44 and PW-1/45, issued by <lb/>the Chartered Accountant of the plaintiff, shows that she <lb/>had a large turnover in the years 2005-06, 2006-07, 2007-<lb/>08 from the services being rendered by her and she incurred <lb/>huge expenditure during those years on advertising the <lb/>services being offered by her, through various clinics. Since <lb/>the defendant has chosen to remain ex parte and has not <lb/>come forward to controvert the oral and documentary <lb/>evidence produced by the plaintiff, I see no reason to <lb/>disbelieve the claim of the plaintiff that the trademark THE <lb/>BODY CARE, on account of its continuous and extensive <lb/>use by the plaintiff through various clinics set up by her <lb/>and the expenses incurred by her and building and <lb/>promoting the trademark, it has come to be associated with <lb/>her and the services being offered under the brand name <lb/>THE BODY CARE have come to be identified as the services <lb/>being offered by the plaintiff. Also, I see no reason to <lb/>disbelieve the claim of the plaintiff that she has been <lb/>recognized as the leader in providing comprehensive beauty <lb/>and health care through a team of dedicated and well-<lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 8 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>trained professionals and, therefore, the persons, who <lb/>choose to buy the services being rendered by her, expect a <lb/>certain professional and ethical standard to be maintained <lb/>by the provider of those services. <lb/>8. <lb/>The Registration Certificate dated 29 th April, 2005, <lb/>in respect of Registration No. A-71352/2005, issued by <lb/>Registrar of Copyrights, shows that the plaintiff is the <lb/>registered owner of the work, annexed to the certificate and <lb/>that she claimed before the Registrar of Copyrights that this <lb/>work was first published by her in India in the year 2000. <lb/>Page 2 of the Certificate, which, in fact, is an annexure to <lb/>the document, shows that the copyright has been claimed <lb/>and registered in the artistic work involved in writing the <lb/>words THE BODY CARE which have been written in a <lb/>particular unique style and particular getup, using a <lb/>distinctive font for the purpose. The sketch of a woman <lb/>drawn by the plaintiff has been shown on the left side of the <lb/>words THE BODY CARE. The picture/sketch of the woman <lb/>is not the photograph of a woman, but is only a sketch <lb/>drawn by the plaintiff. The sketch of a woman drawn by the <lb/>plaintiff does not depict the full body of the woman and her <lb/>hairs are shown flying backwards in a distinct style. The <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 9 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>right arm of the woman is shown touching her left hand. It <lb/>is, therefore, difficult to dispute that the work in respect of <lb/>which copyright has been granted to the plaintiff is a result <lb/>of an idea conceived by her which was expressed in a <lb/>unique way, using a lot of skill, labour and ingenuity in the <lb/>process and, therefore, qualifies as an artistic work within <lb/>the meaning of Section 2(c)(i) of Copyright Act. The work of <lb/>the plaintiff has been recognized by Registrar of Copyright, <lb/>by granting requisite registration in her favour. Prima facie, <lb/>registration of such a work under Copyright Act covered at <lb/>least prima facie evidence of its being an artistic work within <lb/>the meaning of the Act. No one can claim copyright in <lb/>general in the picture or sketch of a woman. However, since <lb/>such a picture/sketch can be drawn in a number of forms <lb/>and using different styles, getups and expressions, a lot of <lb/>skill and labour is involved in conceiving, conceptualizing <lb/>and producing such a work and, therefore, a particular <lb/>picture or sketch may constitute an artistic work in which <lb/>copyright can be claimed by its author. No one has a right <lb/>to reproduce such a work or another work using the <lb/>essential features of that work. <lb/>9. <lb/>A comparison of the work in respect of which <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 10 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>copyright has been granted to the plaintiff with the name <lb/>and logo/image being used by the defendant reveals a <lb/>number of similarities. The sketch of a woman is being <lb/>used by the plaintiff on the left side of the name THE BODY <lb/>CARE. The defendant is also using the sketch of a woman <lb/>on the left side of the name PERFECT BODY CARE. The <lb/>words &quot;SLIMMING AND BEAUTY CLINIC FOR MEN AND <lb/>WOMEN&quot; have been written under the words THE BODY <lb/>CARE in the registered work of the plaintiff. Exactly same <lb/>words have been written by the defendant under the name <lb/>PERFECT BODY CARE, though not in capital letters. The <lb/>font used by the defendant for writing the words PERFECT <lb/>BODY CARE is almost identical to the font used by the <lb/>plaintiff in writing the words BODY CARE. The minimal <lb/>difference in font and shape of the letters can be noticed <lb/>only when both the words are kept side by side and on <lb/>meticulous examination in this regard is carried out. If a <lb/>person having once or more seeing the work of the plaintiff <lb/>comes across the work of the defendant at a later date, <lb/>there is a strong likelihood of his mistaking the work of the <lb/>defendant as that of the plaintiff. Even the colour scheme <lb/>adopted by the parties is similar being pink and white. If <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 11 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>there are substantial similarities in the work, in which the <lb/>copyright is claimed and the impugned work, minor <lb/>dissimilarities will not non suit the plaintiff and <lb/>infringement of the copyright would still be made out. <lb/>10. <lb/>It is not necessary that in order to constitute <lb/>infringement of a copyright, the impugned work should be <lb/>an exact or verbatim copy of the original work and it will be <lb/>sufficient if it is shown that though not a verbatim copy of <lb/>the original work, the impugned work resembles to it in a <lb/>substantial degree by extensive use of the main feature, <lb/>which are found in the work in respect of which copyright is <lb/>claimed. In fact any intelligent person copying a work, in <lb/>which the copyright vests in another person, would make <lb/>some changes here and there so as to claim that his work <lb/>does not constitute infringement of the work in which a <lb/>copyright subsists in favour of another person. But, such <lb/>rather minor dissimilarities between the work of the plaintiff <lb/>and the impugned work would not deprive the plaintiff of <lb/>injunction in case degree of resemblance in the two works is <lb/>substantial and there is an attempt to encash upon the <lb/>goodwill of a well established work. <lb/>11. <lb/>In R.G. Anand v. Delux Films &amp; Ors., AIR 1978 <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 12 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>SC1613, Supreme Court inter alia laid down the following <lb/>propositions: <lb/>One of the surest and the safest test <lb/>to determine whether or not there <lb/>has been a violation of copyright is <lb/>to see if the reader, spectator or the <lb/>viewer after having read or seen <lb/>both the works is clearly of the <lb/>opinion and gets and unmistakable <lb/>impression that the subsequent <lb/>work appears to be a copy of the <lb/>original. <lb/>Whether the theme is the same but <lb/>is presented and treated differently <lb/>so that the subsequent work <lb/>becomes a completely new work, no <lb/>question of violation of copyright <lb/>arises. <lb/>Where however apart from the <lb/>similarities appearing in the two <lb/>works there are also material and <lb/>broad dissimilarities which negative <lb/>the intention to copy the original <lb/>and the coincidences appearing in <lb/>the two works are clearly incidental <lb/>no infringement of the copyright <lb/>comes into existence. <lb/>Thus the artistic representation of the mark/label <lb/>being used by the defendant appears to be a copy of the <lb/>writing style, getup and colour scheme combination being <lb/>used by the plaintiff. <lb/>12. <lb/>The trademark THE BODY CARE is being used by <lb/>the plaintiff since the year 2000. The plaintiff came across <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 13 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>the trademark PERFECT BODY CARE being used by the <lb/>defendant in the second week of November 2008. The <lb/>defendant has not come forward to claim that she was a <lb/>prior user of the words BODY CARE, which forms part of <lb/>her trademark PERFECT BODY CARE. <lb/>The necessary <lb/>inference, therefore, is that it is the plaintiff who is the prior <lb/>user of the trademark THE BODY CARE, she having <lb/>commenced the use in the year 2000. The defendant has <lb/>incorporated almost whole of the trademark of the plaintiff <lb/>by adopting and using the mark PERFECT BODY CARE. <lb/>The defendant has not come forward to explain to the Court <lb/>as to why she chose to include the words BODY CARE in <lb/>the trademark adopted by her. As noted earlier, on account <lb/>of its extensive user since the year 2000 and huge <lb/>expenditure incurred by her on building and promoting the <lb/>trademark THE BODY CARE, this mark has come to be <lb/>associated with the plaintiff. The plaintiff is running a large <lb/>number of clinics throughout the Country offering health <lb/>and beauty care treatment through those clinics. If a <lb/>person, who has availed services of the plaintiff or who <lb/>wants to avail her services on account of the reputation, <lb/>which has come to be associated with her brand THE BODY <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 14 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>CARE, and he happens to come across the mark PERFECT <lb/>BODY CARE being used by the defendant, it is likely to <lb/>cause confusion in his mind and he may presume that the <lb/>clinic being run by the defendant was a clinic of the plaintiff <lb/>or was in some manner or the other associated with her and <lb/>that is why the work BODY CARE is being used by her while <lb/>offering similar services. An unwary consumer, whether <lb/>purchasing goods or availing services attaches considerable <lb/>importance to the essential features of the work or the mark <lb/>as the case may be and the basis to be adopted by the Court <lb/>is as to what the general impression of such a customer of <lb/>imperfect recollection would be on seeing the impugned <lb/>work/mark, where he would consider it to be the <lb/>work/mark of the plaintiff. Hence, there is a genuine <lb/>likelihood of the defendant being able to pass her services <lb/>as those of the plaintiff, by her using the mark PERFECT <lb/>BODY CARE. The case of the plaintiff is that on account of <lb/>high quality of the services being offered by her through <lb/>trained personnel, the customers using her services expect <lb/>them to be of high standard and superior quality. If a <lb/>person avails the services being offered by the defendant, on <lb/>a misconception that she was somehow or the other <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 15 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>connected with the plaintiff and it transpires that the <lb/>quality of the services being provided by the defendant to <lb/>the customer is not as good as the quality of the services <lb/>being provided by the plaintiff, this may not only damage <lb/>the goodwill and reputation of the plaintiff, it may also <lb/>adversely affect the interest of a common citizen to pays for <lb/>services of a high standard but, gets services of a lower <lb/>standard. <lb/>13. <lb/>The word THE BODY CARE of course appears to be <lb/>a descriptive word but, as observed by Supreme Court in <lb/>2005 (30) PTC 1 (SC) even a descriptive word may be entitled <lb/>to protection if it has assumed a secondary meaning which <lb/>identifies it with a particular product or as being from a <lb/>particular source. The case of the plaintiff before this Court <lb/>is that on account of continuous user since the year 2000, <lb/>the efforts made and the expenditure incurred by her on <lb/>building and promoting this mark, it has come to be <lb/>associated with the services being offered by her alone. <lb/>Similar view was taken by this Court in 2002 (24) <lb/>PTC 355 (Del) observing that if a product of a particular <lb/>character or composition is marketed in a particular area or <lb/>place under the descriptive name and has gained a <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 16 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>reputation thereunder, that name which distinguishes it <lb/>from competing products of different composition, the <lb/>goodwill in the name of those entitled to make use of it are <lb/>protected against deceptive use there of the name by <lb/>competitors. In that case, the plaintiff had adopted the <lb/>domain name NAUKRI.COM. The defendant, who adopted <lb/>the domain name NAUKARI.COM had taken the plea that <lb/>the trademark NAUKRI.COM was generic and, therefore, <lb/>incapable of achieving the trademark significance or <lb/>secondary meaning. It was observed during the course of <lb/>judgment that when a defendant does business under the <lb/>name, which is sufficiently close to the name under which <lb/>the plaintiff is trading and the name has acquired a <lb/>reputation, the public at large is likely to be deceived and <lb/>misled that the business of the defendant is business of the <lb/>plaintiff or branch or department of the plaintiff. It was <lb/>further observed that if it is found by the Court that such a <lb/>mark has attained distinctiveness and is associated with the <lb/>business of the plaintiff for a considerable time and <lb/>thereafter the defendant adopts a similar word, to induce <lb/>innocent users to come to its website, which establishes <lb/>dishonest intention and bad faith, the Court would have <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 17 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>justified in granting injunction to the protect business of the <lb/>plaintiff. <lb/>14. <lb/>In Parle Products (P) Ltd. v. J.P. &amp; Co., Mysore, <lb/>AIR 1972 SC 1359, Supreme Court inter alia observed as <lb/>under:-<lb/>According to Karly&apos;s Law of Trade <lb/>Marks and Trade Names (9 th Edition <lb/>Paragraph 838) &quot;Two marks, when <lb/>placed side by side, may exhibit <lb/>many and various differences, yet <lb/>the main idea left on the mind by <lb/>both may be the same. A person <lb/>acquainted with the one mark, and <lb/>not having the two side by side for <lb/>comparison, might well be deceived, <lb/>if the goods were allowed to be <lb/>impressed with the second mark, <lb/>into a belief that he was dealing with <lb/>goods which bore the same mark as <lb/>that with which he was acquainted. <lb/>It would be too much to expect that <lb/>persons dealing with trademarked <lb/>goods, <lb/>and <lb/>relying, <lb/>as <lb/>they <lb/>frequently do, upon marks, should <lb/>be able to remember the exact <lb/>details of the marks upon the goods <lb/>with which they are in the habit of <lb/>dealing. <lb/>Marks are remembered <lb/>rather by general impressions or by <lb/>some significant detail than by any <lb/>photographic recollection of the <lb/>whole. <lb/>Moreover, variations in <lb/>detail might well be supposed by <lb/>customers to have been made by the <lb/>owners of the trade mark they are <lb/>already acquainted with for reasons <lb/>of their own. <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 18 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>It is therefore clear that in order to <lb/>come to the conclusion whether one <lb/>mark is deceptively similar to <lb/>another, the broad and essential <lb/>features of the two are to be <lb/>considered. <lb/>They should not be <lb/>placed side by side to find out if <lb/>there are any differences in the <lb/>design and if so, whether they are of <lb/>such character as to prevent one <lb/>design from being mistaken for the <lb/>other. It would be enough if the <lb/>impugned mark bears such an <lb/>overall similarity to the registered <lb/>mark as would be likely to mislead a <lb/>person usually dealing with one to <lb/>accept the other if offered to him. <lb/>The above referred observations made by the <lb/>Supreme Court in respect of a trademark would equally <lb/>apply in a case for infringement of a registered trademark. <lb/>The plaintiff has, thus, been able to prove <lb/>infringement of her copyright as also that the defendant by <lb/>using the mark PERFECT BODY CARE is passing off her <lb/>beauty and health related services as those being offered by <lb/>the plaintiff. The case of the plaintiff finds further strength <lb/>from the fact that the defendant is provided their services <lb/>from the same premises where the plaintiff was earlier <lb/>running a beauty and health care clinic, thereby giving an <lb/>impression that the clinic was being run by the plaintiff or <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 19 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>was associated with her. <lb/>15. <lb/>The relief of rendition of account was not pressed <lb/>during the course of arguments. The plaintiff has also <lb/>claimed damages to the tune of Rs.20Lacs. No actual <lb/>damages have been proved by the plaintiff and the only <lb/>prayer made during the course of arguments was to award <lb/>punitive damages. The reliance in this regard was placed on <lb/>the decisions of this Court in Time Incorporated v. Lokesh <lb/>Srivastava &amp; Anr., 2005 (30) PTC 3 (Del) and Dabur India <lb/>Ltd. v. Emami Ltd., 2006 (32) PTC 125 (Del). In the case of <lb/>Times Incorporated (Supra), this Court observed that <lb/>punitive damages are founded on the philosophy of <lb/>corrective justice and as such, in appropriate cases these <lb/>must be awarded to give a signal to the wrong doers that the <lb/>law does not take a breach merely as a matter between rival <lb/>parties but feels concerned about those also who are not <lb/>party to the lis but suffer on account of the breach. In the <lb/>case of Hero Honda (Supra), this Court noticing that the <lb/>defendant had chosen to stay away from the proceedings of <lb/>the Court felt that in such case punitive damages need to be <lb/>awarded, since otherwise to the defendant, who appears in <lb/>the Court and submits its account books would be liable for <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 20 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>damages whereas a party which chooses to stay away from <lb/>the Court proceedings would escape the liability on account <lb/>of the failure of the availability of account books. Also, the <lb/>Court needs to take note of the fact that a lot of energy and <lb/>resources are spent in litigating against those who infringe <lb/>the trademark and copyright of others and try to encash <lb/>upon the goodwill and reputation of other brands by <lb/>passing of their goods and/or services as those of that well <lb/>known brand. <lb/>16. <lb/>For the reasons given in the preceding paragraphs, <lb/>the defendant is hereby restrained from offering and/or <lb/>providing beauty and health care services under the name <lb/>PERFECT BODY CARE. The defendant is also restrained <lb/>from using the words BODY CARE as a part of its corporate <lb/>name, in respect of beauty and health care services. The <lb/>defendant will, however, be entitled to use the trademark <lb/>PERFECT BODY CARE as also the tradename PERFECT <lb/>BODY CARE in respect of any services other than beauty <lb/>and health care services such as beauty clinics, health <lb/>clinics, slimming centres, etc. Taking into consideration all <lb/>the facts and circumstances of the case, punitive damages <lb/>amounting to Rs.20,000/-are awarded to the plaintiff. <lb/></body>

			<note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 21 of 21 <lb/></page>

			<body>Decree sheet be prepared accordingly. <lb/>(V.K. JAIN) <lb/>JUDGE <lb/>JANUARY 31, 2011 <lb/>Ag/BG </body>

            <note place="footnote">CS(OS)No. 496/2009 <lb/></note>


	</text>
</tei>
