<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
			<front>IN THE HIGH COURT OF DELHI AT NEW DELHI <lb/>+ <lb/>IA No.245/2004 in CS (OS) No.26/2004 <lb/>% <lb/>Judgment delivered on :03.07.2007 <lb/>M/S G.M. MODULAR PVT. LTD <lb/>.... Plaintiff <lb/>versus <lb/>M/S TM MARKETING (INDIA) &amp; OTHERS <lb/>.... Defendants <lb/>Advocates who appeared in this case:-<lb/>For the Plaintiff <lb/>: Mr S.K. Bansal with Mr Suwarn Rajan <lb/>For the Defendants <lb/>: Mr Amarjit Singh <lb/></front>

			<body>CORAM:-<lb/>HON&apos;BLE MR JUSTICE BADAR DURREZ AHMED <lb/>1. Whether the Reporters of local papers may be allowed to <lb/>see the judgment ? <lb/>Yes <lb/>2. To be referred to the Reporter or not ? <lb/>Yes <lb/>3. Whether the judgment should be reported in the Digest ? <lb/>Yes <lb/>BADAR DURREZ AHMED, J <lb/>1. <lb/>In this application, the plaintiff seeks an interim injunction <lb/>restraining the defendants, etc. from using, manufacturing, selling, <lb/>offering for sale, advertising or displaying directly or indirectly or <lb/>dealing in any other manner or mode in electronic goods, accessories, <lb/>appliances, electronic components and goods of same / similar / allied / <lb/>cognate description thereto under the impugned &quot;TM&quot; trademark / label <lb/>as per Annexure D-A-I or any other trademark / label identical with or <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 1 of 15 <lb/>deceptively similar thereto or bearing the word / mark &quot;TM&quot; either by <lb/>itself or in an artistic manner and the impugned trade dress (Annexure-D-<lb/>B-I) or any other identical or deceptively similar trade dress which would <lb/>amount to or result in passing off and violation of the plaintiff&apos;s &quot;GM&quot; <lb/>trademark / label being (Annexure -A) or passing off and violation of the <lb/>plaintiff&apos;s trade dress / cartons being (Annexure-B). The application also <lb/>seeks injunction against infringement, passing off and violation of the <lb/>plaintiff&apos;s copyrights in the said mark / label / trade dress. <lb/>2. <lb/>Before dealing with the arguments advanced by the counsel for the <lb/>parties, it would be appropriate to set out the nature of the controversy <lb/>and it cannot be better demonstrated than by visually depicting the same. <lb/>The trademark / label of the plaintiff as given in Annexure -A is as <lb/>under:-<lb/>Annexure -A <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 2 of 15 <lb/>The trademark / label of the defendant as per Annexure-D-A-I is as <lb/>under:-<lb/>Annexure -D-A-I <lb/>The trade dress of the box / carton of the plaintiff as per Annexure-B is <lb/>as under:-<lb/>Annexure -B <lb/>The trade dress of the defendant&apos;s box / carton is as under:-<lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 3 of 15 <lb/>Annexure -D-B-I <lb/>3. <lb/>The plaintiff has filed the suit for passing off of the trademark as <lb/>well as for infringement of its copyrights. The plaintiff claims to be the <lb/>proprietor of the trademark &quot;GM&quot; and its artistic label in relation to <lb/>electrical goods, including electrical switches, etc. as per Annexures-A <lb/>and B depicted above. According to the learned counsel for the plaintiff, <lb/>the plaintiff&apos;s company was incorporated on 25.06.1999 and the mark <lb/>&quot;GM&quot; forms a material part of the plaintiff&apos;s trademark, the plaintiff <lb/>company&apos;s name being &quot;GM Modular Private Ltd.&quot; It is stated that the <lb/>plaintiff adopted the trademark &quot;GM&quot; and its label in the year 1999 and <lb/>claims continuous user thereafter. In the plaint, the plaintiff has <lb/>mentioned that it had applied for registration of the trademark. During <lb/>the pendency of the suit, the trademark has been registered. It is stated <lb/>that the plaintiff is now the registered proprietor of the trademark &quot;GM&quot; <lb/>in relation to electrical goods, including electrical switches in Class 09. <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 4 of 15 <lb/>A copy of the trademark registration certificate which was granted during <lb/>the pendency of the suit has been filed alongwith the list of documents <lb/>dated 13.01.2005. The said certificate indicates the details of the <lb/>registration as under:-<lb/>&quot;Trade Mark <lb/>: <lb/>GM Label <lb/>Trade Mark Number <lb/>: <lb/>934452 in Class 09 <lb/>Date of Registration <lb/>: <lb/>26.06.2000&quot; <lb/>4. <lb/>It is also pointed out by the learned counsel for the plaintiff that <lb/>the copyright for the &quot;GM&quot; label is also registered under No.A64280/03. <lb/>The plaintiff has claimed exclusive rights in the trademark &quot;GM&quot; Label <lb/>under Sections 28 and 29 of Trade Marks Act, 1999 and exclusive rights <lb/>in its copyrights on account of its origination under Section 2 (c) of <lb/>Indian Copyright Act, 1956. The plaintiff has also stated that it has built <lb/>up an extensive goodwill and reputation in the trademark &quot;GM&quot;. The <lb/>sales figures for the year 2002-03 indicate sales of more than Rs.76 <lb/>lakhs. A copy of the certificate of approval with regard to quality <lb/>standards conforming to ISO 9001:2000 dated 25.07.2002 has also been <lb/>placed on record. Copies of advertisements appearing in prominent <lb/>magazines as well as in hoardings around the stadia in international <lb/>cricket matches have also been filed. Invoices in respect of the particular <lb/>goods under the trademark / label &quot;GM&quot; commencing from the year 2001 <lb/>have also been filed. Certain government test reports in respect of the <lb/>brand name &quot;GM&quot; have also been filed. The earliest report being of <lb/>31.05.2000. These factors were pointed out by the learned counsel for <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 5 of 15 <lb/>the plaintiff to indicate the extensive use, reputation, goodwill and prior <lb/>adoption and use by the plaintiff of the mark / artistic work. <lb/>5. <lb/>It was contended by the learned counsel for the plaintiff that the <lb/>defendant has adopted a deceptively similar mark / label &quot;TM&quot; in <lb/>relation to similar goods. The defendants&apos; label and trade dress of the <lb/>packing / carton have already been indicated above. According to the <lb/>learned counsel for the plaintiff, the trademark / label of the defendant is <lb/>identical with and / or deceptively similar to the trademark / label of the <lb/>defendant and accordingly, the plaintiff is entitled to an order of <lb/>injunction being issued against the defendant in respect of the use of the <lb/>trademark &quot;TM&quot; and its artistic features. <lb/>6. <lb/>On behalf of the defendants, it has been firstly contended that <lb/>while arguments have been addressed with regard to infringement of a <lb/>registered trademark, there is no pleading with regard to the registration <lb/>of the mark No.934452. Accordingly, the plaintiff is not entitled to <lb/>argue the case of infringement of trademark or to rely upon registration <lb/>No.934452. It was next contended by the learned counsel for the <lb/>defendants that the plaintiff has made certain false statements. It is <lb/>pointed out that while the plaintiff claims to have used the trademark <lb/>&quot;GM&quot; since 1999, the plaintiff&apos;s documents themselves show the <lb/>introduction of the trademark &quot;GM&quot; in May, 2000. The sales tax <lb/>registration is only of 29.02.2000. It was also pointed out that the label <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 6 of 15 <lb/>shown as Annexure-A and Annexure-D-A-I are only portions of the <lb/>labels / marks and not the complete labels. It was next contended on <lb/>behalf of the defendants that the plaintiff has suppressed material facts. <lb/>The plaintiff had earlier instituted Suit No.1068/2003 claiming identical <lb/>reliefs, but that suit was withdrawn on a flimsy ground. The plaintiff has <lb/>not mentioned the filing of the earlier suit and its withdrawal. According <lb/>to the learned counsel for the defendant, this fact in itself disentitles the <lb/>plaintiff to the discretionary relief of injunction. In support of this <lb/>submission, the learned counsel for the defendants relied upon the <lb/>following decisions:-<lb/>&quot;i) Virumal Praveen Kumar v. Gokal Chand Hari <lb/>Chand: 2000 PTC 507; <lb/>ii) <lb/>Fair Deal Corporation Pvt. Ltd v. Vijay <lb/>Pharmaceuticals: 1985 PTC 80; <lb/>iii) Chandra Shashi v. Anil Kumar Verma: 1994 (4) <lb/>Scale 994; <lb/>iv) Indian Bank v. Satyam Fibres India Pvt. Ltd: JT <lb/>1996 (7) SC 135; <lb/>v) <lb/>SPC Naidu v. Jagan Nath: AIR 1994 SC 583; <lb/>vi) Smithkline Beecham &amp; Others v. G.D. Rathore &amp; <lb/>Others: 2002 (25) PTC 243.&quot; <lb/>7. <lb/>The learned counsel for the defendants also submitted that no <lb/>copyright subsists in a font and that the use of &quot;TM&quot; in ordinary letters <lb/>on the part of the defendants does not constitute infringement of a <lb/>copyright. <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 7 of 15 <lb/></body>

			<page>8. <lb/></page>

			<body>The learned counsel for the defendants also submitted that the <lb/>plaintiff&apos;s suit is barred under the principles of Order 2 Rule 2 of the <lb/>Code of Civil Procedure, 1908 (hereinafter referred to as &apos;CPC&apos;). The <lb/>plaintiff had instituted a suit No.854/2003 with respect to the alleged <lb/>infringement of the design of switches as were being sold by the plaintiff <lb/>under the trademark &quot;GM&quot;. According to the learned counsel for the <lb/>defendants, the plaintiff, while instituting the said Suit 854/2003, omitted <lb/>to sue on the alleged cause of action of passing off arising out of the use <lb/>of mark &quot;TM&quot; on the part of the defendant. The plaintiff was entitled to <lb/>claim more than two reliefs, including the relief of passing off and <lb/>having omitted to do so, the plaintiff was not entitled to maintain the <lb/>present suit. It was also contended on behalf of the defendant that the <lb/>defendants&apos; user was prior in time. According to the learned counsel, the <lb/>defendant was in the business of the said goods much prior to the <lb/>plaintiff. The defendant had stated on oath that the mark &quot;TM&quot; was <lb/>being used since 1998 and that merely because the word &quot;TM&quot; is not <lb/>mentioned in the invoices filed on behalf of the defendant does not prove <lb/>that the said mark was not being used by the defendant. <lb/>9. <lb/>Finally, on the key issue of deceptive similarity, it was contended <lb/>on behalf of the defendants that there is no similarity between the label <lb/>marks of the plaintiff and the defendants taken as a whole. It was <lb/>submitted that for the purpose of comparing the competing marks in <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 8 of 15 <lb/>order to decide the question of likelihood of confusion and deception, <lb/>marks are to be compared as a whole. It was also submitted that the <lb/>marks at Annexure-B of the plaintiff and Annexure-D-B-1 of the <lb/>defendant have no similarity. It was also submitted by the learned <lb/>counsel for the defendants that the essential features of the plaintiff&apos;s <lb/>label mark are &quot;G Magic&quot; as against the essential feature of the <lb/>defendants mark &quot;Touch Me&quot;. According to the learned counsel, the <lb/>comparison of the label marks has to be made with reference to the <lb/>essential features of the marks. Reliance was placed on the decisions of <lb/>the Supreme Court in the cases of Corn Products Refining Co. v. <lb/>Shangrila Food Products Ltd: AIR 1960 SC 142 and F. Hoffimann-La <lb/>Roche and Co. Ltd v. Geoffrey Manners and Co. Pvt. Ltd: AIR 1970 <lb/>SC 2062. It was further submitted that the colour combination of the <lb/>Annexures B and D-B-I were totally different and that there were <lb/>sufficient added matters in the label of the defendant to establish <lb/>distinction between the goods of the defendants from that of the plaintiff. <lb/>For this proposition, reliance was also placed on the judgment of the <lb/>Supreme Court in the case of Kaviraj Pandit Durga Dutt Sharma v. <lb/>Navaratna Pharmaceutical Laboratories: AIR 1965 SC 980. It was <lb/>also contended that the test for comparison of the word mark consisting <lb/>of two or three ordinary letters of the English alphabet is different from <lb/>the test applicable to word marks having phonetic similarity. It was <lb/>submitted that the initial letter difference in a short word mark or two <lb/>letter marks is sufficient to distinguish the marks. Reliance was placed <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 9 of 15 <lb/>on an English decision of the Chancery Division reported in 1979 R.P.C. <lb/></body>

			<page>355. <lb/></page>

			<body>10. With regard to the submission of the defendants that the plaintiff <lb/>cannot rely upon the registration of the trademark because of an absence <lb/>of pleading in the plaint, it is relevant to point out that the plaintiff had <lb/>stated in paragraph 12 of the plaint that in order to have statutory rights <lb/>of registration conferred upon it, the plaintiff has duly filed for <lb/>registration of its trademark / label under the Trade and Merchandise <lb/>Marks Act, 1958. The registration of the trademark was granted only <lb/>subsequently during the pendency of the suit. However, once the <lb/>trademark is registered it shall relate back to the date of application as <lb/>mentioned above. Therefore, in my view, there is sufficient pleading in <lb/>the plaint with regard to the registration of the trademark and the <lb/>objection of the defendants is not sustainable. As regards the alleged <lb/>false claims made by the plaintiff with regard to the user of the trademark <lb/>&quot;GM&quot; since 1999, that would be a matter of evidence. At this, prima <lb/>facie, stage, all that needs to be seen is that the plaintiff has been using <lb/>the trademark &quot;GM&quot;. While the plaintiff has filed various documents <lb/>indicating user of the trademark &quot;GM&quot; since at least the year 2000, no <lb/>document whatsoever has been filed by the defendants indicating any <lb/>prior user. The invoices that have been filed by the defendants did not <lb/>mention the trademark &quot;TM&quot; and as of now, there is no evidence on <lb/>record to show that the defendants had a prior user. <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 10 of 15 <lb/>11. As regards the submission that only portions of the labels have <lb/>been indicated in Annexure-A and Annexure-D-A-I, it must be pointed <lb/>out that Annexure-A and Annexure-D-A-I are the trademarks / labels <lb/>which are, in point of fact, to be compared and Annexures-B and D-B-1 <lb/>are the trade dresses of the packing / cartons in which the electrical items <lb/>are sold. Therefore, this plea of the defendants is also not tenable. <lb/>12. As regards the allegation of suppression of the material fact of <lb/>having earlier instituted the suit No.1068/2003 claiming an identical <lb/>relief, it must be pointed out that the earlier suit No.1068/2003 had been <lb/>filed against some of the defendants herein. The plaintiff wanted to add <lb/>further defendants and sought leave of the court to add some more <lb/>parties. The court permitted withdrawal of the said suit with liberty to <lb/>file a fresh suit. The order passed by this court on 11.07.2003 reads as <lb/>under:-<lb/>&quot;11.07.2003 <lb/>Present: Mr S.K. Bansal for the plaintiff. <lb/>S.No.1068/03 <lb/>Counsel for the plaintiff requests for leave to withdraw this <lb/>suit with liberty to file a fresh suit since according to him <lb/>some more parties are to be added. The leave prayed for is <lb/>granted. Suit is dismissed with liberty to file a fresh suit on <lb/>the same subject in accordance with law.&quot; <lb/>Thus, while dismissing the earlier suit, this court had granted liberty to <lb/>the plaintiff to file a fresh suit on the same subject in accordance with <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 11 of 15 <lb/>law. While it is true that the withdrawal of the said suit is not mentioned <lb/>in the plaint, it is not, in my opinion, a material fact in view of the liberty <lb/>granted by this court for filing a fresh suit. <lb/>13. With regard to the submission that the present suit is barred under <lb/>the principles of Order 2 Rule 2 of CPC, it would be pertinent to note <lb/>that two suits had been filed by the plaintiff in 2003, one being suit <lb/>No.1068/2003 and the other being Suit No.854/2003 [renumbered as <lb/>CS(OS) 497/2005]. While Suit No.1068/2003 had been withdrawn, as <lb/>indicated above, with liberty to file a fresh suit after adding certain other <lb/>parties, Suit No.854/2003 [renumbered as CS(OS) 497/2005] was <lb/>continued. The latter suit was for permanent injunction to restrain <lb/>infringement of the registered design, passing off, delivery up, etc. The <lb/>prayers in that suit were different from the prayers in Suit No.1068/2003. <lb/>The causes of action were also distinct. Therefore, this objection of the <lb/>defendants would also not be tenable at this stage. <lb/>14. Coming to the crux of the matter as to whether the trademark / <lb/>label of the plaintiff and that of the defendant is deceptively similar or <lb/>not, it would be pertinent to note that in a recent decision of the Supreme <lb/>Court in the case of Ramdev Food Products Ltd v. Arvindbhai Rambhai <lb/>Patel &amp; Others: 2006 (8) SCC 726, the Supreme Court has observed that <lb/>the test for determining deceptive similarity in an infringement action <lb/>would be the same as in the case of a passing off action. The court <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 12 of 15 <lb/>observed that although the defendants might not be using the actual <lb/>trademark of the plaintiff, the get up of the defendant&apos;s goods may be so <lb/>much like the plaintiff&apos;s that a clear case of passing off could be proved. <lb/>The Supreme Court observed that in a case for infringement where the <lb/>defendant&apos;s trademark is identical with the plaintiff&apos;s mark, the court will <lb/>not enquire whether the infringement is likely to deceive or cause <lb/>confusion. However, in the case of deceptive similarity, the test would <lb/>be as to the likelihood of confusion or deception arising from similarity <lb/>of marks and the test is the same, both in infringement and passing off <lb/>actions. A reference to various decisions cited by the learned counsel for <lb/>the plaintiffs with regard to deceptively similar trademarks would also be <lb/>fruitful. In N. Ranga Rao &amp; Sons v. Anil Garg and Others: 2006 (32) <lb/>PTC 15 (Del), the trademarks &apos;DIA&apos; and &apos;LIA&apos; were held to be <lb/>deceptively similar. In M/s. Pidilite Industries Pvt. Ltd v. M/s. Mittees <lb/>Corporation and Another: 1989 PTC 151, the trademarks &apos;TREVICOL&apos; <lb/>was held to be deceptively similar to the trademark &apos;FEVICOL&apos;. In Asha <lb/>Soap Factory v. Dhanthak &amp; Co. and Another: 1985 Arb. L. R. 176, <lb/>the trademarks &apos;BB&apos; and &apos;88&apos; were held to be deceptively similar. In <lb/>M/s . Hitachi Ltd v. Ajay Kr. Agarwal &amp; Others : 1996 PTC (16) (DB), <lb/>the trademark &apos;Hitashi&apos; was held to be deceptively similar to the <lb/>trademark &apos;Hitachi&apos;. Other decisions of deceptively similar trademarks <lb/>are as under:-<lb/>&quot;i) TISCO and FISCO : 1992 (I) Arbitration Law <lb/>Reporter 417 (The Tata Iron &amp; Steel Co. Ltd., <lb/>versus Mahavir Steels and Ors). <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 13 of 15 <lb/>ii) <lb/>LAKME and LIKE -ME : 1996 PTC (16) 567 <lb/>(Lakme Ltd., Versus Subhash Trading); <lb/>iii) NIREX and MIREX : 1984 PTC 97 (Nirex <lb/>Industries (P) Ltd., Vs Man Chand Foot Wear <lb/>Industries); <lb/>iv) M2 TONE and MV -TONE : 2004 (2) PTC 458 <lb/>(Del) (Charak Pharma Private Limited Vs Prashi <lb/>Sharma Private Limited) ; <lb/>v) <lb/>G.E.C. and A.E.C. : AIR 1974 Punjab &amp; Haryana <lb/>14 (The General Electric Co., Vs Pyara Singh). <lb/>15. The test for determining whether one trademark is deceptively <lb/>similar to another is based on the likelihood of confusion or deception <lb/>arising in the minds of the consumers. Visually comparing the trade / <lb/>label &quot;GM&quot; with the trademark / label &quot;TM&quot;, one finds that they are <lb/>prone to be confused for each other. The background, colour (red) is the <lb/>same. The letters &quot;GM&quot; and &quot;TM&quot; are similar. The manner and style in <lb/>which &quot;GM&quot; and &quot;TM&quot; are indicated are prone to be confused for one <lb/>another. Looking at Annexures-A and D-A-I and comparing the two, <lb/>there is no doubt in my mind that the two are deceptively similar. As <lb/>regards Annexure B and Annexure D-B-I, if the elements of the <lb/>trademarks &quot;GM&quot; and &quot;TM&quot; as indicated in Annexure-A and D-A-I <lb/>(respectively) are removed, there would be no deceptive similarity <lb/>between them (Annexure B and Annexure D-B-I). If the essential <lb/>features as submitted by the learned counsel for the defendants were &quot;G <lb/>Magic&quot; and &quot;Touch Me&quot;, then the defendants ought to have no objection <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 14 of 15 <lb/>to the deletion or removal of the trade mark / label &quot;TM&quot; because even as <lb/>per their submissions, this is not an essential feature. <lb/>16. Accordingly, the plaintiff has been able to establish a prima facie <lb/>case in its favour and the balance of convenience also lies in passing an <lb/>order of injunction whereby the defendants are injuncted from using the <lb/>trademark / label &quot;TM&quot; as indicated in Annexure-D-B-I in respect of the <lb/>products in question. However, the plaintiffs are not entitled, at this <lb/>stage, to any injunction with regard to the trade dress of the box / carton <lb/>as indicated in Annexure-D-B-I. The trade dress, as indicated in <lb/>Annexure D-B-I can continue to be used by the defendants provided the <lb/>trademark / label &quot;TM&quot; is removed therefrom. <lb/>With these directions, this application stands disposed of. <lb/>BADAR DURREZ AHMED <lb/>(JUDGE) <lb/>July 03, 2007 <lb/>δυττ <lb/>IA 245/03 in CS(OS)26/04 <lb/>Page No. 15 of 15 </body>


	</text>
</tei>
